https://www.tipperarycu.ie/privacy-centre/

Opening HoursOpening HoursTipperary Town (HQ)PlasseySt Bernard’s BanshaDoonDundrumFacebookInstagramTwitterYoutubeplayOffice LocationsTipperary Town (HQ)PlasseySt Bernard’s BanshaDoonDundrumContact UsMember Online AccessHow to Join UsHomeMember Online AccessHow to Join UsJoin UsLoansSavingsCurrent AccountOther ServicesNewsContact UsSearch
Menu
Menu NEWSLETTERSIGN UP TO OUR NEWSLETTERX First NameLast NameEmail Privacy Policy*Please take time to read the privacy notices of the credit union which outline how and why we process your personal data. A copy of the credit unions privacy notices can be found clicking on the following link https://www.tipperarycu.ie/privacy-centre/
Please tick to confirm that a copy of the credit unions privacy notice has been made available to you.CAPTCHA
Privacy CentreYou are here: Home1 / Privacy Centre
PRIVACY CENTRE + GDPR
Tipperary Credit Union»Privacy CentreDATA PROTECTION AT TIPPERARY CREDIT UNIONOne of the biggest changes to Irish Data Privacy Law comes into effect on 25th May 2018. On that date, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) will be introduced, to strengthen data protection and to make it easier for you to access your personal information and control how it is used.KEY ASPECTS OF GDPR
As a member of member of Tipperary Credit Union, you frequently share information with us. In doing so we take your privacy seriously and we put a strong emphasis on protecting your data. We understand that you trust us to protect your information and to process, share and retain this data in a secure and confidential manner.THE GDPR will give you greater control over your personal information by setting out additional and more clearly defined privacy rights, which you can exercise. You have rights which allow you to address any concerns or queries regarding the processing of your personal data, including the right to:Be informed about the processing of your personal informationReceive copies of your informationHave inaccuracies/incomplete information corrected and updatedObject to particular use of your personal data for our legitimate business interests or direct marketing purposesIn certain circumstances have your information deleted or our use of your data restrictedExercise the right to data portability i.e. transfer a copy of your information to another providerWithdraw consent at any time where processing is based on consentOur Data Privacy Statement and website (www.tipperarycu.ie) explains how we collect personal information about you, how we use it and how you can interact with us about it.  We may change this notice from time to time, in whole or part, at our sole discretion or to fulfil a legal obligation.HOW HAS TIPPERARY CREDIT UNION PREPARED FOR GDPR? At Tipperary Credit Union, we have prepared for GDPR in a proactive manner. We have been actively implementing the changes required in order to remain compliant under the new regulation. We have demonstrated and documented accountability through a number of technical and organisational measures these include:Appointment of a Data Protection Officer (DPO)Tipperary Credit Union has appointed a Data Protection Officer to oversee the transition into GDPR and act as a point of contact for members, staff and the supervisory authority. Our Data Protection Officer oversees how we collect, use, share and protect your information to ensure your rights are fulfilled.Data Minimisation & Privacy by DesignWe have reviewed and amended existing application forms and updated them accordingly so that they are aligned with the principles of the GDPRPolicy UpdatesWe have reviewed and updated Tipperary Credit Union’s data protection policies and also provided a data protection privacy notice which has been made available to all staff and membersNew Data RegisterWe have conducted a data audit to identify all personal data held by Tipperary Credit Union and recorded the legal basis for processing such dataStaff trainingWe have conducted regular and appropriate staff training for GDPR readinessOutsourcing PoliciesWe have contacted any data processors we share information with to ensure they too are GDPR compliant with their own policies and proceduresRevision of Internal ControlsWe have revised internal controls and undertaken GDPR readiness assessmentsWHAT DOES GDPR MEAN FOR YOU? Tipperary Credit Union has always appreciated your trust in us to collect, process and protect your information. As a data controller and processor of your personal data, we will continue to operate in a transparent manner and continue to minimise the risk of unfair outcomes for our customers or impact on their data rights.   We will continue to safeguard your personal data by maintaining our strong security mechanisms and technologies already in place  as your data security is paramount in our organisation.We will continue to manage processes and systems to improve our level of member service while providing you with the assurance that your information is safe and secure in line with and use your personal date and develop a strong risk culture and putting security at the front of our priority. Tipperary Credit Union takes privacy and the protection of personal data belonging to our members and staff very seriously. We treat information belonging to our members and staff with the highest priority in terms of security and we will continue to implement this strategy going forward. Therefore, we fully support the enhancements to data protection which will be introduced by GDPR.GDPR increases and reinforces the rights of individuals in relation to the information we hold about them. Being transparent and providing accessible information to members about how we process their personal information is a key element of GDPR.What do you need to do?The changes described above are purely to enhance your understanding of GDPR and to clarify your rights under the new regulations. Please take some time to read our updated Privacy Notices below for more detailed information on how we use your information and your rights.NEED MORE INFORMATION? If you have any questions in relation to GDPR, please call us on 062 80400 or email us at dpo@tipperarycu.ie.RIGHT OF ACCESS You have a right to a copy of your personal data held by this credit union. Therefore, you may at any time submit a written subject access request to Tipperary Credit Union by post, fax or email.  The credit union will reply to your request within 1 month of receipt of the written or emailed request.A Subject Access Request should be addressed to:Data Protection Officer, Tipperary Credit Union, Emmet Street, Tipperaryand must include sufficient details to identify the person concerned and to help locate all relevant information. DownloadsGeneral Privacy Notice Lending Privacy NoticeAccount Opening Privacy NoticeDebit Card Privacy PolicyRecruitment Privacy NoticeThird Party  Privacy NoticeData Subject Access Request FormLinksOur Cookie PolicyDisputes and ComplaintsGDPR Information from the Data Protection websiteInformation LeafletsTCU GDPR Information FlyerTCU GDPR Information PosterILCU GDPR Information FlyerIf you have any questions in relation to GDPR, please call us on 062 80400 or email us at dpo@tipperarycu.ie.Useful LinksApply for Current AccountApply for Debit CardOnline Loan ApplicationLoan CalculatorTransfer FundsRegister for Online AccessRequest a CallbackOur OfficesCuonline Help
CU Online LoginContact Us+353 62 80400info@tipperarycu.ieJoin UsLoansSavingsServicesJoinRegulation 76 Framework Contract (PSD2)NewsEventsCareersIntranetOpening HoursSecurity CentrePrivacy CentrePrivacy and CookiesManage Cookie SettingsDisputes and ComplaintsTerms & ConditionsReports & DownloadsFAQUseful LinksFees and Charges
Scroll to top
1800 62 22 62
info@tipperarycu.ie CU Online How To Join UsFacebookInstagramTwitterYoutubeplay
